Daniel Whettam

Interactive AI PhD student at The University of Bristol. I'm interested in machine learning and computer vision, particularly in regards to multi-modal applications. I have research experience in multiple areas of machine learning and deep learning and depth of knowledge in a range of related disciplines including machine learning, deep learning, computer vision and natural language processing. I'm a highly motivated individual who loves to learn and engage with new ideas, and participate within the wider machine learning community.

Education

Academic Qualifications.

The University of Bristol

PhD - CDT in Interactive Artificial Intelligence 2019–Present

The University of Edinburgh

MSc Data Science , Merit 2018–2019

The University of Hull

BSc (Hons) Computer Science, 1st class 2015–2018

Poynton Sixth Form College

A Levels , Computing, Maths, Psychology 2013–2015

Research Projects.

 PhD Summer Project (Ongoing) 'The Blind Camera: Perception of Object Interaction Events from Audio Sensors'

Supervisors: Dima Damen, Vangelis Kazakos I am researcing how to perform egocentric action recognition entirely from audio signals, in the context of the home-kitchen setting¹. Recent work² has demonstrated the importance of audio in a multi-modal approach for egocentric action recognition. This work is investigating the efficacy of audio alone, with the aim of demonstrating that audio sensors provide very rich and informative data, highlighting the perception that audio sensors are more private than cameras is a myth. This project should lead into a complete PhD project on integrating audio with video.

o MSc Dissertation 'Finding the Right Teacher for a Difficult Student'

Supervisors: Amos Storkey, Elliot J. Crowley Investigated the use of Neural Architecture Search models for network distillation, where a smaller *student network* approximates the learnt representation of a larger *teacher network*. Developed a novel approach to creating a teacher network for distillation using Fisher information to scale up a NAS model. Involved extensive implementation in PyTorch.

o BSc Dissertation 'Data Mining Over Cancer Data with Decision Support Tool'

Supervisor: Darryl Davis I researched the use of clinical decision support systems for cancer diagnosis, ultimately developing a decision support tool to assist in bowel cancer diagnosis. This involved substantial data pre-processing, tackling issues of class imbalance and missing data. I engaged with literature regarding clinical decision support systems and the applications of machine learning in a clinical setting.

Professional Experience

Research Experience.

Sci-Tech Daresbury

Research Assistant

STFC Hartree Centre

June 2018-August 2018

Researched applications of transfer learning for deep end-to-end speech recognition systems for use in assisted living environments. Used transfer learning to train RNN's to recognise regional UK dialects. Engaged with relevant literature to learn and understand transfer learning approaches to speech recognition. Applied understanding to a new setting, creating an effective speech recognition system for the Liverpudlian dialect. Presented results to Hartree Centre academics and Data Scientists. Our work from this project has been accepted for presentation at the 2019 Interspeech workshop on Pluricentric Languages in Speech Technology.

Teaching Experience....

Laboratory Demonstrator

Hull

University of Hull

Sept 2016-July 2018

Engaged with students and academics during labs, assisting students with lab work and assignments. Demonstrated for a range of modules including: Artificial Intelligence (Prolog), Advanced Programming (C++), Networking and User Interface Design (C#), Programming (C#).

Publications

Workshop Presentations and Abstracts....

Whettam D., Gargett A., and Dethlefs N.: Cross-dialect speech processing Satellite Workshop at Interspeech 2019: Pluricentric Languages in Speech Technology

Invited Talks

Finding the Right Teacher for a Difficult Student

Apple, Cheltenham, UK

February 2020

An invited talk on my MSc dissertation with particular focus on how network distillation techniques may be applicable to the small scale neural networks used by Siri.

Cross-dialect speech processing

Interspeech 2019, Graz, Austria

September 2019

A talk presenting my work on cross-dialect speech processing at the Interspeech 2019 workshop on Pluricentric Languages in Speech Technology. This work was a result of my research internship at the Hartree Centre.

Conference Attendance and Community Involvement

Interactive Artificial Intelligence Winter School

The University of Bristol, UK

February 2020

Interspeech 2019 - Pluricentric Languages in Speech Technology Workshop

Graz, Austria

September 2019

Deep Learning Winter School

The University of Hull, UK

January 2018

Technical skills

• **Programming Languages/Packages/Frameworks:** Python, PyTorch, NumPy, C++, C#, TensorFlow, Hadoop MapReduce, Keras, SKLearn, Pandas, Stan, Matlab, TeX, Prolog, C, SQL.